Spas Zahariev Software Engineer

spas.zah@gmail.com

07784239930

in linkedin.com/in/SpasZahariev

github.com/SpasZahariev

ttps://spas.work

Summary

Fullstack developer with 2+ years of industry experience. Passionate about cloud infrastructure, design patterns, and clean code. Looking for exposure to more technologies and system paradigms.

Skills

Certifications: Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Associate, Microsoft Azure AZ-900, Unity Game Engine

Languages: Java, Python, C#, C++, Rust, Typescript/Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bash, SQL, Haskell

Technologies: React, Angular, Flutter, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GraphQL, Socket IO, Jenkins, CI/CD, Protobuf, Tensorflow, Spring, Hibernate, Git, Version Control, PostgreSQL, Oracle DB, Dynamo DB

Professional Experience

JPMorgan Chase - Associate Software Developer

Sep 2019 - Present

Java and React developer for internal risk management applications

Owned and refined an epic for offloading account balances from a legacy system

- Implemented a Java Thread pool to consume the incoming balance messages
- Established locking mechanisms for versioning the latest balance information
- · Decommissioned the legacy system, removed overhead, and increased maintainability

Led a critical process optimization that needed to publish 150,000 funding messages per hour

- Used Grafana metrics and environment logs to identify pain points in the workflow
- Utilised Apache Kafka topics, in-memory caches, and Oracle database tables to meet the client requirements for receiving all the latest information within 5 minutes and generating snapshots
- Reduced publication time from 30 minutes to sub 5 minutes by processing asyncronously

Designed and released a new regulatory dashboard application

- Implemented live metric updates for users by using websockets and React Redux
- Automated the generation of custom report layouts and exporting them to Excel with Typescript
- Simplified the auditing process for 200 internal business analysts

JPMorgan Chase - Software Engineer Summer intern

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018

Developed an Angular web app for accessing details about thousands of automated test suites

- Created UI mockups for the visual design and workflows
- Built a Java back-end with Hibernate and a Rest API for fine-grained searches
- · Application got adopted by dev teams as a way to track their projects' status

Education

University of Southampton

Bachelor of Software Engineering • First Class Honours

Sep 2016 - Jun 2019

Sofia High School of Mathematics

Sep 2011 - May 2016

Secondary Education Diploma • 5.91 out of 6.00 (A*)